Guide to the New York University Collection of Contemporary Composers' Websites MSS.496
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Nagorcka, Ron, December 2017- ongoing; Nagorcka, Ron, 1948-; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  The website contains a biography of the artist; information about his compositions and projects; excerpts of reviews of his works; a calendar of his events; a discography of his published albums; and examples of his works in the form of embedded audio files.
  Embedded Squarespace audio player files were not captured due to technological constraints.
  Ron Nagorcka (b. 1948) is an Australian composer of electronic and acoustic music based in Tasmania. Nagorcka's music makes use of traditional indigenous Australian instruments and techniques, as well as digital technologies. In particular, his music is characterized by the use of didgeridoos of his own creation. Examples of recordings released by Nagorcka include Song of the Central Tree, Atom Bomb becomes folk art, Felt, Devils of the Night, and Secret Places.
- Naphtali, Dafna, February 2015-ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of dafna.info in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Dafna Naphtali is a singer, instrumentalist, and electronic musician whose works include experimental and interactive electroacoustic music. She has composed works for multi-channel sound, music robots, Disklavier piano, and site-specific interactive soundwalks. Naphtali is a Professor of Music Technology at NYU Steinhardt, where she has previously taught Max programming, electronic music performance and composition, and soundwalking.
  The artist's website highlights her artistic focus on voice and electronic music. As of March 2025, it contains a biography of Naphtali, press documents; a list of works; information about her participation in ensemble and duo projects; a list of blogs; information about her teaching and consulting; news about the artist; a calendar of upcoming events; and her contact information.
- Nathan, Eric, February 2014- ongoing; Nathan, Eric, 1983-; 2 websites in 2 archived websites
  Robots.txt was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of ericnathanmusic.com and nathanartsmusic.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist; information about his compositions; news and reviews relating to Nathan and his work; a discography of his published albums; examples of his music in the form of embedded audio files; a calendar of his events; and a gallery of images of the artist. The crawl also includes the website for his published music.
  Embedded video and image files on the site were captured, but do not render in the archived copy. Future changes to the Wayback Machine may allow the files to be played.
  Eric Nathan (b. 1983) is a composer of classically-influenced orchestra, chamber, solo, vocal, and choral music.
- Negrón, Angélica, February 2014- ongoing; Negrón, Angélica, 1981-; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of angelicanegron.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Angélica Negrón (b. 1981) is a New York-based Puerto Rican composer and multi-instrumentalist. She has written works for accordions, robotic instruments, toys, and electronics; and for chamber ensembles, orchestras, choir, and film. She is a founding member of the band Balún, and a teaching artist for the New York Philharmonic's Very Young Composers program.
  The website contains a biography, a list of works, videos, and contact information.
- Neill, Ben, February 2014-ongoing; 2 websites in 2 archived websites
  Robots.txt was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of benneill.com and mimigoeseandbenneill.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  As of April 2025, the artist's website contains a biography of Neill; information about the Mutantrumpet; a selection of quotes by the press; information about his compositions and projects; a calendar of his events; his blog; press relating to the artist; and examples of his works in the form of embedded audio and video files as well as prose writings. The crawl also includes the musical collaboration website with vocalist Mimi Goese. The website includes news, musical performances, videos, and music from the collaboration.
  Embedded Spotify files were not captured due to technological constraints.
  Ben Neill (b. 1957) is the inventor and player of the Mutantrumpet, a hybrid electro-acoustic instrument based on the trumpet. He is a composer of instrumental music influenced by jazz, electronica, and classical styles. The Mutantrumpet was initially designed in 1980, and went through a series of developments until its fourth version, which debuted in 2019 in the performance of Fantini Futuro, in Brooklyn, New York. Neill is also the author of a book titled Diffusing Music: Trajectories of Sonic Democratization, which was published in 2024.
- Neuwirth, Olga, September 2017- ongoing; Neuwirth, Olga, 1968-; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of olganeuwirth.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist; information about her compositions; news relating to Neuwirth and her works; a discography of her published albums; information about her concerts; and examples of her prose writings. It also contains embedded audio files of two of her works.
  Olga Neuwirth (b. 1968) is an Austrian composer of classically-influenced orchestra and chamber music. Her repertoire also includes compositions for opera, theater, film, vocalists, and installations. Neuwirth's artistic practice draws inspiration from multiple aesthetic disciplines including film, literature, visual arts, and architecture. Examples of notable works composed by her include The Outcast-Homage to Herman Melville, Das Vaterspiel, Masaot/Clock without Hands, Le Encantadas, Orlando and Eleanor Suite. She is a professor of composition at the University of Music and Performing Arts in Vienna, Austria.
- New York Downtown Scene and other miscellaneous discographies, May 2017-December 2019; cuid5859; Roussel, Patrice, 1956-; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of nyds-discographies.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contained the discographies of composers Tim Berne, Anthony Coleman, Tom Cora, Dave Douglas, Marty Ehrlich, Ellery Eskelin, Fred Frith, Wayne Horvitz, Guy Klucevsek, Steve Lacy, Arto Lindsay, Chirstian Marclay, Ikue Mori, Lawrence "Butch" Morris, David Moss, Evan Parker, Zeena Parkins, Bobby Previte, Marc Ribot, Jon Rose, Ned Rothenberg, Elliott Sharp, David Shea, Otomo Yoshihide, and John Zorn. As of April 2025, it no longer exists.
- Niblock, Phill, September 2017- ongoing; Niblock, Phill, 1933-2024; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Robots.txt was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of phillniblock.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  As of April 2025, the website contains a biography of the artist; information about Experimental Intermedia, the foundation he directed; a discography of his album releases; information about events including concerts performed in celebration of Niblock; and a news section that continues to be updated as of 2025.
  Phill Niblock (1933-2024) was an American multimedia musician and composer of experimental and minimalist instrumental music in the avant-garde style. Niblock was the director of Experimental Intermedia, a non-profit organization based in New York City supporting the work of intermedia artists. His compositional style was characterized by the construction of 24-track digitally-processed monolithic microtonal drones.
- Niv, Yoni, September 2017-ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Robots.txt was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of yoniniv.org in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website was captured between 2017 and 2018. It contained a biography of the artist; information about his compositions, research, and teaching; and a calendar of his events. As of April 2025, the website contains a biography of the artist; news about upcoming events; information about his artistic and musical projects accompanied by embedded audio files; a list of projects that he curated; information and videos of the ensemble Musica Nova; and details about the focus of Niv's scholarly and teaching practices.
  Yoni Niv is a composer, multimedia artist, and scholar who creates computer music and sound installations in the new music style. His works mix improvisation with scored performance. Niv's artistic practice focuses on time-based art and the creation of cyclical, non-linear experiences. As a scholar, Niv currently focuses on the study of the "relation between sound and the formation of the subject of psychoanalysis." He has served as co-artistic director of Musica Nova, an Israeli new music ensemble. He is also the co-founder of The Advanced Study Program for Experimental Music and Sound Art in Jerusalem.
- Norman, Andrew, February 2015-ongoing; Norman, Andrew, 1979-; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of andrewnormanmusic.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Andrew Norman (b. 1979) is a composer of classical music, an educator, and musical advocate based in Los Angeles. Norman's compositions include chamber, orchestra, solo, vocal works, and opera. In 2017, he was selected as Composer of the Year by Musical America. As a teacher, Norman has participated in educational residencies and composed pieces for young audiences such as the children's opera A Trip to the Moon.
  The website highlights Norman's roles as a composer and an educator. As of March 2025, it features a biography, a list of works, information about his teaching accompanied by images, and contact information.
- Nytch, Jeffrey, April 2014- ongoing; Nytch, Jeffrey, 1964-; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of www.jeffreynytch.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Jeffrey Nytch (b. 1964) is a composer, performer, and educator. He has composed works for orchestra, chorus, and solo instruments. Some works in his repertoire include Acclamations, Epilogue: In Memoriam Yitzhak Rabin, Novas, and Symphony No. 1: Formations. Nytch is also a strategic consultant for arts organizations and educational institutions, as well as the author of the book titled The Entrepreneurial Muse: Inspiring Your Career in Classical Music. As an educator, he was a Professor of Composition at the University of Colorado-Boulder, where he served as Director of the Entrepreneurship Center for Music. Nytch also served as Managing Director of the Pittsburgh New Music Ensemble (PNME).
  The website contains information about Nytch's compositions, workshops, consulting, and his book The Entrepreneurial Muse: Inspiring Your Career in Classical Music. It also contains a biography of the artist, his blog, and contact information. This description was updated in March 2025.
- O'Halloran, Dustin, April 2014-ongoing; O'Halloran, Dustin, 1971-; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of dustinohalloran.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Dustin O'Halloran (b. 1971) is a pianist and composer of film and television scores based between Reykjavík and Los Angeles. O'Halloran is a member of the musical duo A Winged Victory for the Sullen with Adam Wiltzie. His latest solo work, the album titled 1 0 0 1, was released in 2024. It includes violin, an eight-voice choir, electronics, and the participation of the Budapest Art Orchestra. O'Halloran's recent works for film and television include titles such as Bridget Jones: Mad About the Boy, Ammonite, and The Old Guard.
  The website contains a news page, a biography, a list of works, a list of live performances, a store, and contact information. This description is based on the February 2023 crawl of the website.
- O'Regan, Tarik, February 2014- ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Tarik O'Regan (b. 1978) is a British and American composer based in San Francisco, California. His compositions are influenced by his Arab and Irish heritages; and include music for orchestra, soloist, and chorus, as well as electronic and dance music. His work has been recognized with two Grammy award nominations and he is the recipient of two British Composer Awards. O'Regan is also a writer and his pieces were featured in the BBC Radio series The Essay.
  The website contains news, performances, audio, videos, a discography, stage works, a complete list of works, contact information, a press kit, information on purchasing scores, and links to the composer's social media pages. The description is based on the Jan 2023 crawl.
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of tarikoregan.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website was rescoped to also include wisemusicclassical.com domains.
- Oliver, Jaime E., April 2014- ongoing; Oliver La Rosa, Jaime E., 1979-; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of jaimeoliver.pe in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Jaime E. Oliver (1979) is a composer and sound artist who specializes in computer music and electronic arts. His pieces include compositions for instruments, interactive systems, and live sound performances. He also creates sound objects, installations, computer musical instruments, and develops open source software. Oliver is also an academic researcher focusing on "the changes in how out concepts of musical instruments have changed over the course of the 20th century as well as the role played by Latin America in the creation of musical Avant Gardes." Among his creations are included Silent Drum and Mano, two open source systems that continuously track and classify hand gestures.
  The website contains a biography, a list of works, software documentation, courses, publications, and contact information. The description is based on the Feb 2023 crawl.
- Pallett, Owen, April 2014-ongoing; Pallett, Owen, 1979-; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Owen Pallett (b. 1979) is a Canadian composer, violinist, keyboardist, and vocalist who used to be known by the pseudonym Final Fantasy. Some of Pallett's titles include The Butcher, Fire Mare, Paragon of Order, and A Bloody Morning. His album He Poos Clouds was awarded the Polaris Music Prize in 2006.
  As of February 2023, the website contains a list of tour stops, a catalog of works, recordings, and contact information.
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of owenpalletteternal.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
- Pàmies, Joan Arnau, February 2014-ongoing; cuid5854; Pàmies, Joan Arnau, 1988-; 2 websites in 2 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of joanarnaupamies.com and pamies.info in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Site crawls of http://joanarnaupamies.com were discontinued in May 2017 because the site was taken down by the owner.
  Joan Arnau Pàmies' previous website, which was located at http://joanarnaupamies.com, no longer exists. It contained a biography of the artist; examples of his works in the form of embedded audio and video files; a calendar of his events; and examples of Pàmies' prose writings. His current website, which is located at https://pamies.info, contains a biography with images of the artist; a list of works; a list of albums; videos with excepts of his works and recordings of live presentations; press reviews; and his contact information.
  Joan Arnau Pàmies (1988-) is a composer, record producer, and performer of the new-music genre. He was born in Catalunya, Spain, and introduced to music as child by his parents. His compositions combine traditional instruments with new techniques and accessories to create experimental performance pieces, which include a variety of genres such as electronic music, jazz, modernism, and noise rock. Pàmies is also the founder of the label Protomaterial Records and has an academic background that has led him to give presentations at universities and conservatories such as Columbia University, Goldsmiths, University of London, UNAM (Mexico City), University of Nottingham, Harvard University, and Real Conservatorio Superior de Música (Madrid).
- Pann, Carter, February 2015-ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of carterpann.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Carter Pann (b. 1972) is a pianist and composer of solo, vocal, chamber, orchestral, and wind ensemble music. He currently conducts the Boulder Altitude Directive contemporary music ensemble at the University of Colorado in Boulder, where he also serves as a professor of musical composition. Some of Pann's titles for piano include The Bills, She Steals Me, Fantasy-Inventions, and White Moon Over Water.
  As of March 2025, the website contains a link to Pann's catalog of works, a PDF with details about his piano music, professional head shots of the artist, a biography, and a link to his profile in the University of Colorado Boulder's College of Music webpage.
- Pape, Andy, March 2020-ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of andypape.dk in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Andy Pape (b. 1955) is an American composer based in Denmark. He creates opera, symphonic, and chamber music. His work is inspired by a variety of musical sources such as avant-garde, performance theater, jazz, and rock music. His two-act opera Other Buildings, which was the culmination of his composing residence at the Funen Opera in Odense, received the Reumert award for best opera in 2015.
  As of March 2025, the website features Pape's CV; a list of opera; symphonic and chamber music works; examples of his works in the form of embedded audio and video files; and a calendar.
- Parkins, Zeena, April 2015-ongoing; cuid5941; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of zeenaparkins.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  As of April 2025, the website contains a biography of the artist; her CV; press photos; details about the electronic harp that she designed; events listings; information about her projects; and a list of her recordings as composer, collaborator, and instrumentalist.
  Zeena Parkins (b. 1956) is a contemporary composer and improviser of electroacoustic music. Her pieces, played on traditional and electric harps, piano, and accordion, have strong inspirations from rock, jazz, and free improvisation. She is also known for having designed a series of custom-made electric harps. Parkins has often worked in collaboration with other artists, including Björk and Yoko Ono.
- Paterson, Robert, April 2014- ongoing; Paterson, Robert, 1970-; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Robert Paterson (b. 1970) is a conductor, percussionist, and composer of contemporary classical music based in Saratoga Springs, New York. His works are primarily atonal and programmatic, and include orchestral, large chamber, opera, choral, and vocal chamber pieces. Paterson's music is influenced by ecological themes and nature; in particular, the classical elements of earth, water, air, and fire. He is also an advocate for animal rights and the environment, which he celebrates through compositions such as Triple Concerto, A New Earth, Listen, and I Go Among Trees.
  The website contains a biography, a list of works, performances, recordings, press coverage, writings, and contact information. This description is based on the Jan 2023 crawl.
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of robertpaterson.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
- Patterson, Michael, April 2014-July 2021; Patterson, Michael, 1958-; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of michaelpattersoncomposer.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contained a biography of the artist, information about his teaching, compositions, and projects, a calendar of his events, his blog, a press kit, a discography and filmography of his published works, and examples of his music in the form of embedded audio files. Capture of the site began in April 2014. This description is based on the December 2017 capture of the site. In 2020, the website redirected to an index of the original website. The website ceased to exist on the live web in 2021.
  Pop-up windows containing embedded audio files were not captured due to technological constraints.
  Michael Patterson (b. 1958) is a New York-based composer of music across a wide variety of genres, including orchestral; film and television scores; jazz; chamber; and jingles. Some of his notable works include Caching Light, Strange Beauty, Samvaad, Parallel Forms, and Psalm. Patterson also works as a producer, arranger, and composer for the record label IPO and is a member of the international composing and performance group Improvisatory Minds. He is also the recipient of a Grammy and an Emmy award.
- Pavone, Jessica, September 2017-ongoing; 2 websites in 2 archived websites
  Robots.txt was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of jessicapavone.com and jessicpavone.tumblr.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The crawl was rescoped to also include Blogspot domains.
  The website contains a biography of the artist; information about her compositions and projects; a discography of her published albums; examples of her compositions in the form of embedded video files; information about the J. Pavone Ensemble; news and reviews about Pavone and her works; a gallery of images of the artist; a calendar of events; and a performance archive.
  The crawl also includes captures of Pavone's Tumblr blog.
  Jessica Pavone (b. 1976) is a New York-based composer and instrumentalist. Her pieces cover a variety of styles including jazz, chamber, avant-garde, and experimental music. Pavone's compositional practice is primarily characterized by her pieces for solo viola. In 2017, she created the improvisational group J. Pavone String Ensemble. Examples of Pavone's pieces for solo viola include Performance Novels, When No One Around You is There but Nowhere to be Found, Only in Dreamz, Aednat, Salute Flying, and Knuckle Under.
- Payne, Maggi, September 2017-June 2023; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Robots.txt was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of sites.google.com/site/maggipayne in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contained a biography of the artist; information about her compositions and projects; a discography of her published albums; news and reviews about Payne and her works; a gallery of images of the artist; and information about her awards, education, and credits. As of April 2025, the website does not exist at this URL.